Finding Aid for the Waldo Salt Papers, 1936-1987
UCLA Library, Performing Arts Special Collections
- UNPRODUCED FILMS
  - HEMINGWAY
    - Research Material
      - Research on E.Hemingway. "II": 1934-36. Incl. typed biographical data from various sources; photocopies of articles in books, magazines, journals and newspapers; with dates of research and index. 23 items. (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Research on E.Hemingway. "III": 1937-39. Incl. typed biographical data from various sources; photocopies of articles in books, magazines, journals and newspapers; with dates of research and index. 30 items. (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Research on E.Hemingway. "IV": 1940-48. Incl. typed biographical data from various sources; photocopies of articles in books, magazines, journals and newspapers; with dates of research and index. 30 items. (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - Research on E.Hemingway. "V": 1949-53. Incl. typed biographical data from various sources; photocopies of articles in books, magazines, journals and newspapers; with dates of research and index. 20 items. (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Research on E.Hemingway. "VI": 1954-55. Incl. typed biographical data from various sources; photocopies of articles in books, magazines, journals and newspapers; with dates of research and index. 17 items. (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - Research on E.Hemingway. "VII": 1956-60. Incl. typed biographical data from various sources; photocopies of articles in books, magazines, journals and newspapers; with dates of research and index. 14 items. (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - Research on E.Hemingway. "VIII": 1961. Incl. typed biographical data from various sources; photocopies of articles in books, magazines, journals and newspapers; with dates of research and index. 9 items. (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - Research on E.Hemingway. "IX": 1961. Incl. typed biographical data from various sources; photocopies of articles in books, magazines, journals and newspapers; with dates of research and index. 11 items. (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - Research on E.Hemingway. "X": 1962-63. Incl. typed biographical data from various sources; photocopies of articles in books, magazines, journals and newspapers; with dates of research and index. 12 items. (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - Research on E.Hemingway. "XI": 1964-66. Incl. typed biographical data from various sources; photocopies of articles in books, magazines, journals and newspapers; with dates of research and index. 18 items. (Box 44, Folder 4)
      - Research on E.Hemingway. "XII": 1967-72. Incl. typed biographical data from various sources; photocopies of articles in books, magazines, journals and newspapers; with dates of research and index. 17 items. (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - Research on E.Hemingway. "XIII": 1973-76. Incl. typed biographical data from various sources; photocopies of articles in books, magazines, journals and newspapers; with dates of research and index. 9 items. (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - Research on E.Hemingway. "XIV": 1977. Incl. typed biographical data from various sources; photocopies of articles in books, magazines, journals and newspapers; with dates of research and index. 22 items. (Box 44, Folder 7)
      - Research on E.Hemingway. "XV": 1978. Incl. typed biographical data from various sources; photocopies of articles in books, magazines, journals and newspapers; with dates of research and index. 26 items. (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Research on E.Hemingway. "XVI": 1979. Incl. typed biographical data from various sources; photocopies of articles in books, magazines, journals and newspapers; with dates of research and index. 26 items. (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Clippings: "A Farewell to F.Scott" (The New York Times, April 1978); "Miro at 85" (The New York Times, 4/15/78); "Mary Hemigway" (Soho Weekly News, 4/6/78); and copy of Cuban newspaper "Granma", 7/11/77. (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - "Oversize articles": photocopies and clippings from newspapers and magazines, 1937-78, incl. index. 31 items. (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - "Ernest Hemingway. The Life and Death of a man", by A.Aronowitz and P.Hamill, 196l. 222p. (Photocopy). (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - "Hemingway. The Writer's Art of Self-Defense", by J.Benson, 1969. 202p. (Photocopy). (Box 45, Folder 6)
      - "Ernest Hemingway. Critique of Four Major Novels", by C.Baker, 1962. 199p. (Photocopy). (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - "Hemingway's Spanish Tragedy", by L.Broer, 1973. 131p. (Photocopy). (Box 45, Folder 8)
      - "Ernest Hemingway. An Introduction and Interpretation", by S.Baker, l967. 150p. (Photocopy). (Box 45, Folder 9)
      - "Hemingway's Craft", by S.Grebstein, 1973. 244p. (Photocopy). (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - "Ernest Hemingway and the Pursuit of Heroism", by L.Gurko, 1968. 246p. (Photocopy). (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - "Death of a Hunter" (play), by Rolf Hochhuth, n.d., 101p. (Photocopy of typed manuscript). (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - "Hemingway. The Inward Terrain", by R.Hovey, 1968. 248p. (Photocopy). (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - "Hemingway and the Dead Gods. A Study in Existentialism", by J.Killinger, 1960. 114p. (Photocopy). (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - "Hemingway on Love", by R.Lewis, 1965. 252p. (Photocopy). (Box 46, Folder 6)
      - "Hemingway Screened: The Hollywood Version", by F.Laurence, n.d. (Photocopy of incomplete typed manuscript of essay, pp.9-69 and 341-387). (Box 46, Folder 7)
      - "Papa. Hemingway in Key West", by J.McLendon, 1972. 222p. (Photocopy). (Box 46, Folder 8)
      - "Twentieth Century Interpretations of "A Farewell to Arms", ed. by J.Gellens, 1970. 120p. (Photocopy). (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - "The Merrill Studies in "A Farewell to Arms", ed. by J.Graham, l971. Incomplete: pp. III-82p. (Photocopy). (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - "Twentieth Century Interpretations of "The Old Man and the Sea", ed. by K.Jobes, 1968. 120p. (Photocopy). (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - "The Narrative Pattern in Ernest Hemingway's Fiction", by C.Nahal, 197l. 244p. (Photocopy). (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - "Hemingway's First War. The Making of "A Farewell to Arms", by M.Reynolds, 1976. 309p. (Photocopy). (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - "A Hemingway's Check List", by L.Samuels, 1951. 63p. (Photocopy). (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - "Hemingway. A Collection of Critical Essays", ed. by R.Weeks, 1962. 180p. (Photocopy). (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - "Three Bags Full. Essays in American Fiction", by P.Young, 1967. Incomplete: pp. VII-75. (Photocopy). (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - "Ernest Hemingway. A Reconsideration", by P.Young, 1966. 244p. (Photocopy). (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - "Ernest Hemingway", by P.Young, n.d. Incomplete: pp. 80-297. (Photocopy). (Box 47, Folder 10)
      - Transcript of interview with George Saviers during W.Salt's trip to Idaho in April 1979, 42p. (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Script Material
      - Hand-written outlines and notes on drawing paper concerning E.Hemingway's biography in connection with plot structure of screenplay; notes on characters and scenes; chronologies of historical events. n.d. [presumably 1977]. 42 items. (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Hand-written outlines and notes on drawing paper concerning plot structure and approach to subject-matter; notes on characters and scenes. n.d. [presumably 1977]. 18 items. (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - Hand-written outlines, notes and sketches on large drawing paper concerning plot structure; notes on characters and scenes. n.d. [presumably 1977]. 6 items. (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - Hand-written outlines and notes on transparent drawing paper concerning plot structure and scenes; notes on the E.Hemingway character. n.d. [presumably 1977]. 4 items. (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Hand-written and typed outlines and notes regarding plot structure, scenes and dialogue; notes on characters. 1977-78. 49 items. (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Water-color sketches of human figure, incl. one self-portrait [?] or E.Hemingway [?]. 6 items. (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Typed and hand-written notes on approach to script; notes on plot structure, characters, scenes and flashback device; continuity and rewrite notes, incl. revisions and annotations, chronologically arranged, l977-79. (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - Master File, May-June l977. Incl. correspondence on copyright matters, April-May 1977; 2 MGM memos about W.Salt's trip to Havana with Sydney Pollack, July 14/18, l977; chronology of E.Hemingway's life, from various sources (folder 1 of 2). (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - Master File, May-June l977. Incl. correspondence on copyright matters, April-May 1977; 2 MGM memos about W.Salt's trip to Havana with Sydney Pollack, July 14/18, l977; chronology of E.Hemingway's life, from various sources (folder 2 of 2). (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - Master File, November l977-May l978. Script, incl. continuity notes, notes on Spain and places and events related to plot; transcript of narration from Joris Ivens's "The Spanish Earth" (l937); notes on rewrites and flashback device (folder 1 of 2). (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - Master File, November l977-May l978. Script, incl. continuity notes, notes on Spain and places and events related to plot; transcript of narration from Joris Ivens's "The Spanish Earth" (l937); notes on rewrites and flashback device (folder 2 of 2). (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - Master File, April-August l978. Script, incl. continuity notes and notes on sequences (folder 1 of 2). (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - Master File, April-August l978. Script, incl. continuity notes and notes on sequences (folder 2 of 2) (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - Master File, August-November l978. Script, incl. continuity and outline notes, with revisions and annotations (folder 1 of 2). (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - Master File, August-November l978. Script, incl. continuity and outline notes, with revisions and annotations (folder 2 of 2). (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - Master File, November l978-February l979. Script, incl. continuity notes, notes on characters and scenes (folder 1 of 3). (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - Master File, November l978-February l979. Script, incl. continuity notes, notes on characters and scenes (folder 2 of 3). (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Master File, November l978-February l979. Script, incl. continuity notes, notes on characters and scenes (folder 3 of 3). (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Master File, May-August l979. Script, incl. continuity notes, notes on characters, scenes and African setting (folder 1 of 3). (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Master File, May-August l979. Script, incl. continuity notes, notes on characters, scenes and African setting (folder 2 of 3). (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Master File, May-August l979. Script, incl. continuity notes, notes on characters, scenes and African setting (folder 3 of 3). (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Script ("Original"), April l978-February 1979, 407p. (folder 1 of 2). (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - Script ("Original"), April l978-February 1979, 407p. (folder 2 of 2). (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Script ("Draft II"), June-July 1979, 178p. Incl. annotations. 2 copies: one missing pages 39, 67, 81, 110, 145, 147, 154, 160 and 164. (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Script, August l979, 147p. (2 copies). (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Revised draft, September 1982, 147p. (Same as box 38, folder 3). Note on cover: "Based on the book "How It Was" by Mary Hemingway". (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Redrafted pages from script "Draft II" (38-3), with annotations and corrections, dated (folder 1 of 2). (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Redrafted pages from script "Draft II" (box 38, folder 2), with annotations and corrections, dated (folder 2 of 2). (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Uncollated script materials with annotations, corrections and revisions, various dates, l978. (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Uncollated script materials with annotations, corrections and revisions, various dates, l978. (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Uncollated script materials with annotations, corrections and revisions, various dates, l978. (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - Uncollated script materials with annotations, corrections and revisions, various dates, l978-79. (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - Uncollated script materials: extra pages from Master File in box 37, folders 3/4/5, various dates, l979. (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Uncollated script materials, with annotations and corrections, various dates, l978. (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - Uncollated script materials, various dates, l978. (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - Typed and hand-written notes on scenes and characters, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - IVANHOE
    - Script Material
      - Script, "First draft continuity", 4/26/48. 179p. (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - THE LAST FRONTIER
    - Script Material
      - Master File, July-September 1963. Incl: script, notes on characters and scenes, rewrite notes, with annotations and dates (folder 1 of 2). (Box 66, Folder 4)
      - Master File, July-September 1963. Incl: script, notes on characters and scenes, rewrite notes, with annotations and dates (folder 2 of 2). (Box 66, Folder 5)
      - Script, July-August 1963, 175p. Annotated. Note on cover page: "Salt new pages". (Box 67, Folder 1)
      - Script, September 1963. 173p. Annotated. (Box 67, Folder 2)
      - Script material: rewrite notes, 9/15/63; comments on script, n.d., 5p; revised pages for producer Harold Hecht, 8/8/63. (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - THE LONELY PASSION OF JUDITH HEARNE
    - Notebook
      - Conceptualization of film's plot, characters and dialogue, on sketch paper. Mostly text with few drawings. n.d. (18x24) 2 items. (Box 126, Folder 4)
    - Research Material
      - "Observations upon the Irish" (essay) in "Time" magazine, June 20, 1969, pp.37-38; "The United Irishman" (pamphlet), Dublin, October 1969, 6p. (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Script Material
      - Outline and notes on Brian Moore's novel and his two script versions; outline of W.Salt's screenplay; continuity notes, notes on characters and plot, transcript of discussion with producer I.Kershner, rewrite notes, with annotations and corrections. (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Outline and continuity notes, discussion with producer Irvin Kershner, notes on rewrite, various dates, l969. (3 sets. Same as box 30, folder 7 but incomplete). (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Master File, April-June l969. Script, incl. outline and continuity notes, notes of meeting with producer Irvin Kershner, and rewrite notes. (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - Master File, July l969-March l970. Script, incl. continuity notes and notes on rewrite (folder 1 of 2). (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - Master File, July l969-March l970. Script, incl. continuity notes and notes on rewrite (folder 2 of 2). (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - Script, May-June l969. 160p. (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Script ("Final"), February-March l970. 111p. (2 copies). (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Uncollated script materials, with annotations and corrections, April-May l969. (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Uncollated script materials, with annotations and corrections, May l969. (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Uncollated script materials, with annotations and corrections, May-June l969. (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Uncollated script materials, with annotations and corrections, June l969. (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Uncollated script materials, with annotations and corrections, August l969-March 1970. (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Uncollated script materials, with annotations and corrections, June l969-February 1970. (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Uncollated script materials, with annotations and corrections, August l969-February 1970 (Different from 33-3). (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - Uncollated script materials, with annotations and corrections, May l969-February 1970. (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - Uncollated script materials, with annotations and corrections, February 1970. (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - 135 index cards with notes on characters, situations, dialogue, props, etc. (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - Hand-written notes on characters, scenes, dialogue, some with editing indications. 10 items. (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - Script:"The Lonely Passion of Judith Hearne", by Brian Moore. 1st draft screenplay, n.d. 87p. (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - Script: "The Lonely Passion of Judith Hearne", by Brian Moore. 2nd draft ("Last") screenplay, n.d. 110p. Annotated by W.Salt. (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - MONSIEUR COGNAC
    - Notebook
      - Notes and sketches for "M.Cognac" project, incl. drawings, n.d. (Two items). (Box 110, Folder 4)
    - Script Material
      - Two versions of treatment: 9/20/62, 62p; 9/22/62, 61p. (Box 68, Folder 3)
      - Uncollated script materials, l962-63. (folder 1 of 2). (Box 68, Folder 4)
      - Uncollated script materials, l962-63. (folder 2 of 2). (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - RED LIGHT, GREEN LIGHT
    - Script Material
      - Script, n.d., with annotations. 304p. (Box 72, Folder 4)
      - Script, incomplete, n.d., with annotations. 286p. (Same as 72-4). (Box 72, Folder 5)
      - Script, n.d., with annotations. 165p. (Box 72, Folder 6)
      - Script, n.d., for producer Victor D. Solow, entitled "The Moon and Mr.Hanna". 133p. (Shorter version of 73-1). (Box 73, Folder 1)
      - Hand-written and typed drafts, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2)
      - Script, incomplete, n.d., no paging; typed and hand-written notes on plot and dialogue, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 8)
  - REVELATIONS
    - Correspondence
      - Correspondence with director Jack Clayton about W.Salt's delays in finishing the screenplay, due to personal and professional reasons, April 1980-January 1983. 7 items. (Box 80, Folder 42)
      - Legal correspondence with Paramount Pictures, Jennorah Productions, Inc., and Paul Kohner/Mike Levy Agency, regarding contract and payments to W.Salt for "Revelations" screenplay, 1979-81. 8 items. (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Script Material
      - Notes on "Revelations", novel by Phyllis Naylor, and script, 1979-80. Incl: outline of novel, 2 copies (one annotated), 13p; notes on structure and characters of novel; continuity notes, various dates; notes on suggested cuts and revisions, 11/24/80. (Box 54, Folder 10)
      - Master File, December 1979-September 1980. Script, incl. outline and notes on novel; background notes on characters and plot (folder 1 of 2). (Box 55, Folder 1)
      - Master File, December 1979-September 1980. Script, incl. outline and notes on novel; background notes on characters and plot of script (folder 2 of 2). (Box 55, Folder 2)
      - Master File, September-November 1980. Script, incl. notes on plot, with some annotations. (Box 55, Folder 3)
      - Master File, November-December 1980. Script, incl. notes on suggested cuts and revisions by director Jack Clayton, 11/24/80; two letters from J.Clayton to W.Salt regarding shortening of script, November 24-25, 1980. (Box 55, Folder 4)
      - Script, May-November 1980. 161p. (Box 55, Folder 5)
      - Script, 12/15/80. 125p. 2 copies (original and photocopy). (Box 56, Folder 1)
      - 1st draft screenplay, 12/19/80. Note on cover: "Revised by Jack Clayton". (Box 56, Folder 2)
      - Notes by Jack Clayton. Incl: general notes on novel; two letters from J.Clayton to W.Salt regarding script dated November 1980; two lists of suggested cuts and revisions: one "major" (7p), other "specific" (29p). (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - 55 index cards with notes on characters and scene breakdown. (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - Notes on structure and characters. Incl: hand-written notes and sketches on oversize drawing paper; miscellaneous notes. 5 items. (Box 56, Folder 5)
      - Photocopy of "Revelations" (novel) by Phyllis Naylor (1979), 275p. (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - THE ROAD TO ROME
    - Script Material
      - Script, "temporary complete", 9/15/39. 114p. In collaboration with Robert Thoeren. (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - ROGUES RUN
    - Script Material
      - Script materials: scene-sequence outline, n.d, 28p, with annotations; script, "rough draft", 8/20/49, 122p; script, "revised temporary", for Norma Productions, 8/20/49, 113p, with annotations and hand-written notes. (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - STILWELL
    - Correspondence
      - Drafts and copy of letter by W.Salt to George Roy Hill, Paul Newman et al., concerning cancellation of project, 7/30/86; correspondence regarding script and research, incl. copy of letter from historian Barbara Tuchman to P.Newman, 10/19/84. 9 items. (Box 81, Folder 8)
      - Legal correspondence regarding Writer Loanout Agreement between Warner Bros. and Jennorah Productions to write "Stilwell" screenplay, January 1985. 3 items. (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Research Material
      - Photocopies of the J.Stilwell Collection index (Hoover Institution Archives, Stanford). Incl: photocopy of letter from archivist to R.Crawford regarding W.Salt's involvement with the project, 10/8/85. (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - Research at the Hoover Institution Archives, Stanford, by Carol Corwen, September l985. Incl: correspondence concerning progress of research and availability of material; and photocopies of J.Stilwell's diaries, chronologically arranged. (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Chronology of Joseph Stilwell's life, 9/9/85 (9p); notes on "Walkout with Stilwell in Burma" by F.Dorn (11p) and "The Stilwell Papers" (47p); tape transcripts of interview with T.White (5 tapes), 9/23/85, and of Stilwell seminar (4 tapes). (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - Letter to W.Salt from J.Levin regarding project, 8/2/84; notes on "J.Stilwell and the American Experience" by B.Tuchman; "The Soong Dynasty"; "In Search of History"; and "Thunder Out of China" by T.White. (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - Photocopy of "The Powers that Be" by D.Halberstam, dealing with Joseph Sitwell, T.White and Henry Luce (pp.100-129). (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Photocopies of newspaper articles regarding Joseph Stilwell, 1942-46. 17 items. (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Photocopies of newspaper articles regarding Chiang Kai-Shek, 1931-1943. 13 items. (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Photocopies of maps of China and Burma. 7 items. (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous newspaper and magazine clippings concerning Chinese history and politics, 1985. (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - Audiotapes of interview with T.White. Labeled and dated (Transcriptions in box 52, folder 3). 6 tapes. (Box 113, Folder -)
    - Script Material
      - Outline, April 1986, incl.continuity notes, 5p. (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - Continuity notes, April l986. Two different versions: one, 54p, with extensive annotations and corrections; the other, 56p, dated 4/8/86. (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - Continuity notes, April-May l986. Various versions and reworkings, arranged chronologically; notes dated 5/19/86 are a copy of annotated draft dated 5/14/86. (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - Continuity notes, April-May l986. Incl: final version of all continuity notes for project; and note on use of voice-over device. Various dates and pagings. (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - 235 index cards with notes on historical background, chronology, characters, situations and settings. (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - TULKU
    - Correspondence
      - Correspondence regarding Loanout Agreement between Warner Bros. and Jennorah Productions, Inc. (W.Salt); various letters and materials regarding research for project, August l983-January 1985. (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - Research Material
      - Photocopy of "On Top of the World. Five Women Explorers in Tibet", by Luree Miller (1976). (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Notes on Tibet and China. Incl: photocopy of article on Chinese poetry; typed overview on historical relationships between both countries; several typed and hand-written notes on social and religious customs in China. (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - Audiotapes (microcassettes) of research material for "Tulku" script. Some labeled and dated. 10 tapes. (Box 113, Folder -)
    - Script Material
      - Outline of "Tulku" (novel) and continuity notes; notes on characters and plot; story conference notes; rewrite notes; with dates and annotations, l983-85. (Box 48, Folder 4)